cahealthbenefitsexchange.com 2014-04-30

# Privacy Policy

Home » Privacy Practices 

* * *

### Notice of Privacy Practices 

## Your Information. Your Rights. Our Responsibilities.

This notice describes how your personal information may be used and disclosed and how you can get access to this information.  

Please review it carefully.

We collect personal information about you. Some examples of the personally identifiable information we collect include:

  * Contact information
  * Social Security Number
  * Demographic information
  * Health information
  * Financial information
  * Alien status

We limit the collection of personal information to what is relevant and necessary to accomplish our lawful purpose, defined in the California Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. When we collect your personal information, we follow all applicable laws and regulations. 

When it comes to your personal information, you have certain rights. This section explains your rights and some of our responsibilities to help you.

**Get a copy of your records** | 

  * You can ask to see or get a copy of your records and other personal information we have about you. Ask us how to do this or visit [www.CoveredCA.com/Privacy/Access](http://www.coveredca.com/Privacy/Access).
  * We will provide a copy or a summary of your records, usually within 30 days of your request. We may charge a reasonable, cost-based fee.

---|---  
**Ask us to correct your records** | 

  * You can ask us to correct your records if you think they are incorrect or incomplete. Ask us how to do this or visit [www.CoveredCA.com/Privacy/Correction](http://www.coveredca.com/Privacy/Correction). 
  * We may say "no" to your request, but we will tell you why in writing within 60 days.

**Request confidential communications** | 

  * You can ask us to contact you in a specific way (for example, home or office phone) or to send mail to a different address. Ask us how to do this or visit [www.CoveredCA.com/Privacy/Communication](http://www.coveredca.com/Privacy/Communication). 
  * We will consider all reasonable requests, and will say "yes" if you tell us you would be in danger if we do not.

**Ask us to limit what we use or share** | 

  * You can ask us not to use or share certain personal information for enrollment or our operations. Ask us how to do this or visit [www.CoveredCA.com/Privacy/Restrict](http://www.coveredca.com/Privacy/Restric). 
  * We may not be able to agree to your request if it would affect your enrollment or our operations.

**Get a list of those with whom we've shared information** | 

  * You can ask for a list (accounting) of the times we've shared your personal information, who we shared it with, and why. Ask us how to do this or visit [www.CoveredCA.com/Privacy/Accounting](http://www.coveredca.com/Privacy/Accounting).
  * We will provide one accounting a year for free but will charge a reasonable, cost-based fee if you ask for another one within 12 months.

**Get a copy of this privacy notice** | 

  * You can download copy of this notice at any time or view it at [www.CoveredCA.com/Privacy/Privacy.pdf](https://www.coveredca.com/Privacy/Privacy.pdf). 

**Choose someone to act for you** | 

  * If you have authorized someone to represent you or if someone is your legal guardian, that person can exercise your rights and make choices about your personal information. Ask us how to do this or visit [www.CoveredCA.com/Privacy/Authorize](http://www.coveredca.com/Privacy/Authorize). 
  * We will make sure the person has this authority and can act for you before we take any action.

**File a complaint if you feel your rights are violated** | 

  * You can complain if you feel we have violated your rights by contacting us or visiting [www.CoveredCA.com/Privacy/Complaint](http://www.coveredca.com/Privacy/Complaint). 
  * You can also file a complaint with the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Office for Civil Rights by sending a letter to 200 Independence Avenue, S.W., Washington, D.C. 20201, calling 1-877-696-6775, or by visiting [www.hhs.gov/ocr/privacy/hipaa/complaints/](http://www.hhs.gov/ocr/privacy/hipaa/complaints/). 
  * We will not retaliate against you for filing a complaint.

For certain personal information, you can tell us your choices about what we share. If you have a clear preference for how we share your information in the situations described below, talk to us. Tell us what you want us to do, and we will follow your instructions. 

**In these cases, you have both the right and choice to tell us to:** | 

  * Share information with your family, close friends, or others involved in payment for your care 
  * Share information in a disaster relief situation 
  * Contact you for fundraising efforts 

_If you are not able to tell us your preference, for example if you are unconscious, we may go ahead and share your information if we believe it is in your best interest. We may also share your information when needed to lessen a serious and imminent threat to health or safety._  
  
---|---  
  
* * *  
  
**In these cases we never share your information unless you give us written permission:** | 

  * Marketing purposes 
  * Sale of your information 

How do we typically use or share your personal information? We limit the use and disclosure of your information to the minimum amount needed to perform our functions. We typically use or share your personal information in the following ways. 

**Determine your eligibility** | We may disclose your personal information with other governmental agencies to determine your eligibility for premium assistance or other insurance affordability programs.  | _Example: We may share your personal information with the IRS to determine your eligibility for advance premium tax credits.  _  
---|---|---  
**Manage your enrollment in health coverage  ** | We may use your personal information and share it with our contractors to enroll you in a health plan and for our operations.  | _Example: We may share your personal information with a contractor who helps develop and maintain our information systems. 

Example: We may share personal information with the health plan you enroll in. 

_  
**Facilitate your enrollment in health coverage** | We may use your personal information and share it with our contractors to help with your enrollment and contact you when necessary. All of these contractors undergo a fingerprint and background check as well as receive specialized training on keeping your information confidential. | _Example: We may share your personal information with a contractor, such as a [Certified Insurance Agent or a Certified Enrollment Counselor](https://www.coveredca.com/enrollment-assistance/), to follow up on your application or to assist you if you have requested help._  
**Create a more personalized experience** | Information collected through one of our programs or services may be combined with other information we have in order to offer you a more personalized experience. | _Example: We may use your information to determine your location and offer you customized services._  
  
How else can we use or share your personal information?

We are allowed or required to share your information in other ways – usually in ways that contribute to the public good, such as public health and research. We have to meet many conditions in the law before we can share your information for these purposes. 

**Help with public health and safety** | 

  * We can share your personal information for situations such as preventing disease or reducing a serious threat to anyone's health or safety.

---|---  
**Do research** | 

  * We can use or share your information for research.

**Comply with state or federal law** | 

  * We can share information about you with the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services if it wants to see that we're complying with federal privacy law.
  * We can share information about you in response to a Public Records Act request, as allowed by the California Information Practices Act.

**Respond to lawsuits and legal actions** | 

  * We can share information about you in response to a court or administrative order, or in response to a subpoena.

We are required by law to maintain the privacy and security of your personal information.

We will let you know promptly if a breach occurs that may have compromised the privacy or security of your information.

We must follow the duties and privacy practices described in this notice and give you a copy of it.

We will not use or share your information other than as described here unless you tell us we can in writing. If you tell us we can, you may change your mind at any time. Let us know in writing if you change your mind.

Covered California utilizes secure electronic interfaces when sharing personally identifiable information electronically.

* * *

**Changes to This Notice.** We can change the terms of this notice, and the changes will apply to all information we have about you. The new notice will be available upon request and on our website at [www.CoveredCA.com/Privacy](http://www.coveredca.com/Privacy). 

* * *

**Data quality and integrity.** We will take steps to ensure that personally identifiable information is complete, accurate, and up-to-date to the extent necessary for its intended purposes and has not been altered or destroyed in an unauthorized manner.

* * *

Safeguards. We will protect personally identifiable information with operational, administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to ensure its confidentiality, integrity, and availability and to prevent unauthorized or inappropriate access, use, or disclosure. These safeguards ensure:

  * The confidentiality, integrity, and availability of personally identifiable information created, collected, used, and/or disclosed by Covered California;
  * Personally identifiable information is only used by or disclosed to those authorized to receive or view it;
  * Tax Return information is kept confidential under section 6103 of the Internal Revenue Service Code;
  * Personally identifiable information is protected against any reasonably anticipated threats or hazards to the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of such information;
  * Personally identifiable information is protected against any reasonably anticipated uses or disclosures of such information that are not permitted or required by law; and
  * Personally identifiable information is securely destroyed or disposed of in an appropriate and reasonable manner and in accordance with retention schedules.

* * *

**Accountability.** We will implement and adhere to these practices through appropriate monitoring and other means and methods to report and mitigate non-adherence and breaches. We will monitor, periodically assess, and update the security controls and related system risks to ensure the continued effectiveness of those controls.

We maintain a system that receives, investigates and responds to complaints from individuals concerning non-compliance with applicable privacy requirements, as reflected in relevant law or regulation, policies and procedures and/or contract. Based on our review, we will use the information received through the complaint process to implement or request appropriate corrective action to address the issue identified in the complaint. We will also use the information received through the complaint process to, improve our safeguards of personal information, and to monitor and improve our operations. 

Referred to collectively as our "Website," Covered California operates and/or maintains several websites including, but not limited to, www.CoveredCA.com, [https://v.calheers.ca.gov](https://v.calheers.ca.gov/), [www.hbex.ca.gov](http://www.hbex.ca.gov/), and [www.healthexchange.ca.gov](http://www.healthexchange.ca.gov/). Use of our Website is subject to the Terms and Conditions of Use available at www.CoveredCA.com/Privacy/Terms, which may change without notice. 

Rev. Date: 3/5/2014
